Gathering data is always the first step in data wrangling.
جمع البيانات دائمًا هو الخطوة الأولى في تعارض البيانات.
The idea is before gathering,
الفكرة أن قبل عملية الجمع،
we have no data and after it, we do.
ليس لدينا بيانات وبعدها يكون لدينا.
This is sometimes called acquiring your data, or collecting it.
يسمى هذا أحيانًا الحصول على بياناتكم أو جمعها.
Gathering captures the spirit of the task best, in my opinion.
في رأيي، تعكس عملية جمع البيانات روح المهمة بالشكل الأمثل.
A bit of a scurrying is often required plus some unexpectedness.
مطلوب القليل من الإسراع في كثير من الأحيان إضافة إلى بعض من عدم التوقع.
Yeah for sure. As you saw my personal example I had to download
نعم بالتأكيد. كما رأيتم مثالي الشخصي، كان عليّ تحميل
three datasets and scrape data off of a web page to fill in missing values.
ثلاث مجموعات من البيانات واستخلاص البيانات من صفحة ويب لملء القيم المفقودة.
It was a lot of scurrying around.
هناك الكثير من الإسراع في الأرجاء.
And depending on where you find your data and what format it's in,
استنادًا إلى أين تعثر على بياناتك ونوع تنسيقها،
the steps of the gathering process can vary.
يمكن أن تتنوع خطوات عملية جمع البيانات.
If the data is in a file,
إذا كانت البيانات موجود في ملف،
gathering often means downloading the file and
فإن عملية الجمع تعني تحميل الملف
importing it into your programming environment like a Jupyter Notebook.
واستيراده إلى بيئة برمجية مثل تطبيق Jupyter notebook.
Yes, exactly.
نعم، بالضبط.
This is what we'll do on our walk through.
هذا ما سنفعله في مسيرتنا.
Other methods of gathering are things like collecting
طرق أخرى للجمع هي أشياء مثل جمع
data from files and databases which is what you'll usually do in the workplace.
البيانات من الملفات وقواعد البيانات التي عادة ما تقوم بها في مكان العمل.
Or you can scrape data off a website or get it from an API,
أو يمكنكم استخلاص البيانات من موقع الويب أو الحصول عليها من API
which stands for application programming interface.
الذي يرمز إلى واجهة برمجة التطبيقات.
APIs let us programmatically access data from applications like Twitter and Facebook.
تمكننا واجهات API من الوصول للبيانات برمجيًا من التطبيقات مثل Twitter و Facebook.
There are even more on top of that.
هناك أكثر من ذلك.
But let's stay focused and get to our walk through.
لكن لنبق مركزين ونذهب في وجهتنا.
Gathering data is fun to me because it can vary so
إن جمع البيانات أمر ممتع لأنه يمكن أن يتنوع
widely but we'll get to the fancier methods in Lesson 2 of the course, so stay tuned.
على نطاق واسع ولكننا سنصل إلى طرق أكثر تميزًا في الدرس 2 من الدورة التدريبية، لذا ابقوا منتبهين.
For now we're going to download a file from a website
في الوقت الراهن، سنحمل ملف من موقع ويب
and import it into our programming environment.
ونستورده إلى بيئتنا البرمجية.